<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of the burrough of Dunwich in Suffolk upon their election of members to serve in the convention appointed to meet the 22d. of January 1689.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B18634</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99825638</idno>
  <idno type="VID">206660</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2264207154</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1022</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99825638</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99825638e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B18634)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 206660)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1791:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of the burrough of Dunwich in Suffolk upon their election of members to serve in the convention appointed to meet the 22d. of January 1689.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Election law --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Dunwich (England) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="appeal">
            <pb facs="tcp:206660:1"/>
            <head>THE CASE OF THE BURROUGH OF Dunwich in Suffolk, Ʋpon their Election of Members to serve in the <hi>Convention</hi> Appointed to meet the 22d. <hi>of</hi> January 1689.</head>
            <p>THIS Burrough chooseth by Prescription, and not by Charter, and had Bailiffs before they were a Corporation.</p>
            <p>Their first Charter was granted by King <hi>John,</hi> which hath been renewed in divers Kings Reigns; Whereby <hi>The Good Men of Dun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wich</hi> are made a Corporation, and have divers Franchises and Priviledges grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed unto them; as to be quit of Toll, Portage, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but no mention is made in any of them of Elections to Parliament.</p>
            <p>About 25 years since the Magistrates began to make profit by Selling Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms of the Corporation, and the Benefit of their Priviledges, granting the same by Deed, under the Seal of the Corporation, to divers Cole-traders and other persons living in <hi>Ipswich, Yarmouth, Norwich,</hi> and other temoter places, who upon shewing the Common Seal have had Allowances made them according<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and in some late Elections have been admitted to Vote; being above Four hundred in number.</p>
            <p>Upon Notice given of the Election upon the <hi>Prince</hi>'s <hi>Letter,</hi> about Three hundred of these, being above thrice as many as the Inhabitants, came to the Election and claim'd a Poll, which was not denied them.</p>
            <p>The Opinions of the most Eminent and Indifferent Council hath been taken, concerning the Right of these Foreign Freemen, to Vote in Elections; who say,
<list>
                  <item>I. <hi>That the Right of Choosing is as antiently it was, in the Inhabitants, only, and that the Charters of Incorporation have no Influence upon it.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>II. <hi>That the Charters being granted to the Men of</hi> Dunwich, <hi>with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out a Power expressed, To make Foreigners free; such Freedoms granted to Foreigners, are as to the Corporation it self, an abuse, and void.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>III. <hi>That it is not in the Power of the Magistrates to inlarge the Number of Electors, by constituting Foreign Freemen, as many and whom they please.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>However they thought fit to make the following Return, <hi>Viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>CHosen, according to the most Antient Custom, by the Majority of the Free Burgesses inhabiting within this Burrough, the Honourable</hi> Roger North <hi>and Sir</hi> Thomas Allen, <hi>to be Representatives,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And also Chosen by a lesser number of Burgesses, residing within the Burrough, and by the Major part of the Freemen of the Corporation, who live out of the Burrough, Sir</hi> Philip Skippon <hi>and Sir</hi> Robert Rich, <hi>to be likewise Representatives,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>The said Return is under the Common Seal, according to Custom, and it is humbly hoped, that the said Mr. <hi>North</hi> and Sir <hi>Thomas Allen,</hi> in right of all the Inhabitants of the said Burrough, may be admitted to Sit and Act in the said Convention, according to the Trust reposed in them, they being first named:</p>
            <p>The rather, Because, unless the Persons chosen by the Inhabitants, be allowed to Sit, it may be pretended that the said Burrough, will have no Representatives, in this Convention.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>